Raven Wei

LinkedIn | ravenwei730@gmail.com | (347) 940-6735 | New York, NY | Portfolio

PROJECTS

Identifying Optimal Advertising Markets | Seaborn | A/B Testing

Live Site | GitHub

Utilized Sampling, Frequency Distributions, Summary Metrics, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn on survey data from entry level
programmers to develop three optimal advertising strategy for an e-learning company that provides online courses in
programming and data science.

Trending Data Science Topics | Web Scraping | Data Visualization

Live Site | GitHub

Analyzed core topics in data science, using Python, APIs and Web Scraping, and Data Visualization, to indicate that deep
learning is a rapidly growing field in data science that sparked a strong initial interest since 2016 and isn't just a passing trend.

Market Insights: Population Data Analysis | SQL | Exploratory Data Analysis

Live Site | GitHub

• Explored the CIA Factbook's global data to summarize world and regional population data, revealing trends in population growth, density, fertility, and mortality to derive market insights utilizing SQL, and Exploratory Data Analysis.

Investigating Fandango Movie Ratings | Statistical Analysis | Matplotlib

Live Site | GitHub

• Utilizing Python and Statistical Analysis to uncover potential skew and bias in Fandango ratings, revealing trends and potential inflation. Leveraged libraries such as Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib to predict future rating projections.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Pandas, NumPy, SQL, Command Line
- Technologies: Jupyter Notebook, Azure Synapse Excel, Analytics, Power BI, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Git
- Methodologies: Exploratory Data Analysis, API and Web Scraping, Probability and Statistical Analysis, A/B Testing

EXPERIENCE

Asian Creative Foundation - New York, NY

Jul. 2022 - Present

Business Analyst, Strategy

 Devised strategic fundraising plans, cultivating successful corporate donor relationships via targeted prospect research and outreach to align interests for impactful financial results.

Tianfu Greenway - Chengdu, CN

Jun. 2021 - Jun. 2022

Business Analyst, Urban Parks Planning

- Devised strategic fundraising plans, cultivating successful corporate donor relationships via targeted prospect research and outreach to align interests for impactful financial results.
- Led research involving economic, cultural, and business analyses for urban park planning initiatives, architecting business processes that contributed to the design and development of 6 new urban parks.
- Identified areas of opportunity for growth, designing and facilitating over 20 brand and community building events that resulted in more than 10,000-foot traffic and several new sponsorships.
- Developed strategies for business growth, marketing, and distribution of cultural and lifestyle products by collaborating with designers and stakeholders, yielding a million-dollar deal for the company.

The FLAG Art Foundation - New York, NY

Dec. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Curator Assistant Intern, Exhibitions

 Managed exhibitions for renowned artists, curated immersive art experiences, conducted thorough research on artists, and analyzed trends to cultivate public engagement for the foundation.

Royal Oak Foundation - New York, NY

Aug. 2019 – Feb. 2020

Business Analyst Intern, Business Development

• Conducted research and analysis in corporate prospecting to provide insights that contributed to the successful fundraising for the 45th Anniversary Gala and Stowe restoration project.

EDUCATION

Dataquest – Data Analytics (Python, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite3)

New York, NY

Pratt Institute – Master of Arts and Culture Management

New York, NY

Sichuan University – Bachelor of Literature in Artistic Designing

Chengdu, CN